# **MURTEDA AYYED GZAR**

201 Yesler Way, Seattle, WA 98104 | H: 319-936-2225 | mortadagzar@gmail.com

### Summary

Web developer with more than 4 years of well-rounded experience . working in multiple Web programming languages/tools/technologies such as HTML,CSS, JavaScript,Python, jQuery, Canvas, Angular, PHP, SQL,Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop and After Effect.certified by University of Washington coding boot-camp.

#### Skills

- Build web frontend solutions using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Angular JS, Bootstrap and other web development technologies.
- Assist in the development, maintenance, and integration tasks of databases in SQL Server.
- designing, developing, and supporting enterprise-class web solutions.
- Experience with User Interface design along with automated systems experience using business logic.
- excellent knowledge of browsers, editors, graphic design software (After effect, PhotoShop, Illustrator, webflow) and with animation software and image optimization.

### Experience

Web Developer

Mango Motion — Seattle, WA

Jan 2018 to Mar 2018

- Create applications that address the phases of SDLC (software development life cycle)
- Develop comprehensive application testing procedures
- Update existing applications to meet the security and functionality standards as outlined in the company's website policies
- Implement testing tools that monitor the ongoing performance of the company website
- Assist in updating application development policies to ensure that all future applications meet the latest technical requireme
- Worked with customers to present mockups and collect information for adjustments.

Web Marketing specialist

Jan 2015 to Jan 2018

ALL THE BEST — Seattle, WA

- Website and software application designing, building, or maintaining.
- Using scripting or authoring languages, management tools, content creation tools, applications and digital media.
- Conferring with teams to resolve conflicts, prioritize needs, develop content criteria, or choose solutions.
- Developing or validating test routines and schedules to ensure that test cases
- mimic external interfaces and address all browser and device types.
- Editing, writing, or designing Website content, and directing team members who produce content.

web developer Apr 2014 to Jan 2015

#### SOUTH OIL COMPANY — Basra, Iraq

Curriculum developer for the web development programming course, responsibilities include; course development, lecture preparation, and development of practical application exercises for web development.

Reservoir digital modeling engineer Apr 2006 to Feb 2014 Iraqi Drilling Company IDC — Basra, Iraq Using reservoir engineering software :#C, Petra, Prosper, GAP, MBAL, Saphir, Aeries to create digital geological 3D models.

## **Education and Training**

Bachelor of Science, Digital Modeling University of Baghdad-engineering college — Baghdad, Iraq, Iraq	2005
Master of Science, Information Technology Shat Alarab college — Basra, Basra, Iraq	2009